## **Brian Alt**

Austin, TX 78745 214-763-5566 brian alt@hotmail.com

# **Summary**

Highly skilled at improving productivity through creating and implementing more efficient work processes. Known for being dedicated to tasks at hand with a talent for meeting deadlines. Ability to adapt technical skills and personnel management experience to successfully execute broad-ranging client projects.

### **Notable Skills**

- 8 years management experience in various professional environments
- Basic HTML, CSS and JavaScript knowledge
- Experience with FME 2013/2015 Workbench
- Experience with Oracle's SQL Developer
- 6 year experience utilizing ESRI Arc 10.x for creating, advanced editing and validation of spatial data
- Comfortable working both in groups and independently
- Proficient at reading and understanding legal description, survey notes and plats for major land survey systems
- Extensive knowledge of US land survey systems (PLSS, Metes and Bounds, Districts and Texas Abstracts)

# **Professional Experience**

#### Data Analyst P2 Energy Solutions

1355 Central Pkwy S #500, San Antonio, TX 78232

· January 2013 – September 2016

Supervise the Digital Ownership team (4 employees) to maintain client expectations and needs. Focus on providing the highest quality of data with the most value added benefits for the end users

- Set project timelines and track operator progress to ensure timely completion
- Plan, develop and lead training sessions on new workflows, technique improvement and software use for the department and individuals
- Determine department priorities
- Work closely with management on planning, budgeting and department issues
- Generate weekly productivity reports for office management and executives
- Conduct quality control and assurance checks weekly and prior to data release to clients
- Lead departmental meetings
- Develop and implement training plan for department new hires and cross training employees

### **GIS Analyst** Texas Department of Transportation

118 East Riverside, Austin, TX 78704

· March 2018 - Present

- Collect, prepare, digitize and code spatial data into GIS format
- Conduct mapping research to ensure accurate use of data and resolve conflicting information
- Create and maintain cartographic products using ArcGIS
- Create, maintain and update GIS databases using the ESRI suite of ArcGIS software
- Maintain Roadway Inventory data within Geospatial environment
- Interpret source documents, such as engineering plans, plot maps and legal descriptions and enter required data into the GIS
- Provide technical assistance and support for GIS projects, applications and data
- Plan, lead and track major projects with in the department and agency

#### GIS Technician Apex Contractor - Apple, Inc.

12565 Riata Vista Cir, Austin, TX 78727

· October 2016 - October 2017

Responsible for content analysis, validation, cleansing, collection, and reporting. Analyze and validate data content and assemble new content from various sources, including databases, files/spreadsheets, and websites. Respond to data inquiries from various groups within an organization.

## **Military Experience**

#### **United States Army**

10 point VA Rating

### Platoon Squad Leader

Fort Lewis, WA

· May 2005 - February 2006

Responsible for the welfare and readiness of team members in preparation for rapid deployment; enforced soldier discipline in garrison and field training exercises; responsible for the employment, accountability, and readiness of a Reconnaissance Vehicle, weapons, and equipment valued at \$2.5M.

#### **Vehicle Commander**

Fort Lewis, WA

- April 2004 - May 2005

Responsible for the maintenance and operation of a STRYKER combat vehicle, operated heavy machine gun during combat patrol, navigated for the squad leader, and monitored communication traffic between other vehicles and ground units, took control of vehicle movement in the absence of the squad leader.

#### Training Room NCO

Fort Lewis, WA

· November 2004 - May 2005

Carried out the commander's plans and programs for the accomplishment of the unit's training objectives and missions, drafted training schedules, maintained unit training files, prepared requests for training areas, ranges, and other items required to support scheduled training, managed the companies allocations for numerous schools.

## **Education**

### **Austin Community College**

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

· August 2019

## Pennsylvania State University

Post Baccalaureate Certificate - Geographic Information Systems

September 2011

## **University of Texas at San Antonio**

Bachelor of Arts - Geography Bachelor of Arts - Political Science August 2011

· May, 2009